CATEGORICAL, ORDINAL AND INTERVAL VARIABLES:
A categorical variable (sometimes called a nominal variable) is one that has two or more categories, but there is no intrinsic ordering to the categories.  
For example, gender is a categorical variable having two categories (male and female) and there is no intrinsic ordering to the categories. 

An ordinal variable is similar to a categorical variable.  The difference between the two is that there is a clear ordering of the variables.
For example, suppose you have a variable, economic status, with three categories (low, medium and high).  

An interval variable is similar to an ordinal variable, except that the intervals between the values of the interval variable are equally spaced.  
For example, suppose you have a variable such as annual income that is measured in dollars, and we have three people who make $10,000, $15,000 and $20,000.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Dummy variables trap:
Sex_female	Sex_male	
0		1
1		0
0		1
0		1
The two features are independent, so we just need one feature. Sometimes there exists three or more features are indepedent, so we can drop one of them.
